二零二一年，云南省初中。
学业水平考试英语听力测试
现在开始。
做题时，先将答案标在试题卷上。
first. After sheet.
录音内容结束后，请将试题卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
第一节：听下面五个句子，从题中所给的
A, B, C Listen each sentence twice.
三个选项中选出与所听句子内容相关的图画。
听完每个句子后，你将有五秒钟的作。
答时间，每个句子听两遍。
A, A, A, A, 5.
The boy is helping the old woman cross the street
第二节，听下面五个句子，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出与所听句子内容相符的正确答语。
听完每个句子后，你将有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每个句子听。
6. What are you going to be when you grow up,
7. Let me help you take these books to the classroom.
8. Do you want to visit a science museum with me next Sunday?
9. Our school football team lost the game at the last minute yesterday.
10. Can you tell me how far it is from your home to school?
11. Can you tell me how far it is from your home to school?
第三节，听下面五段对话。
每一段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你将有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读。
下一小题：每段对话听两遍。
11. tell how it 12.
Can you tell me is your home to school?
12. Hi, Mike.
I can't find my dictionary.
Did you see it?
12. Hi, Mike.
I can't find my dictionary.
Did you see it?
13. Excuse me, sir,
which bus will take me to the post office?
Excuse me, sir, which bus will take me to the post office?
14. bus office?
14. Hi, Lucy.
I went to the music club last night but didn't see you there.
15. Hi, Lucy.
16. mother had a terrible cough and I stayed at home to look after her.
mother 17. it's just 3 o 'clock now.
The concert will start in 40 minutes.
Oh, my watch shows me the wrong time.
Hurry up, John.
We will be late for the concert.
20. Take your time, Gina.
It's just 3 o now.
The concert will start in 40 minutes.
21. my watch shows me the wrong time.
节听下面两段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前。
前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白听两遍。
听第一段材料，回答。
第十六、十七小题。
shows time. what a beautiful paper cutting you have,
哇哦，
you. I've been learning to do paper cutting in a nearby village.
I like it so much.
Why do you like it?
By doing paper cutting, I can know more about Chinese culture.
Yeah, it's really fun to learn by doing something.
Wow, what a beautiful paper cutting you have,
you. I've been learning to do paper cutting in a nearby village.
I like it so much.
Why do you like it?
By doing paper cutting, I can know more about Chinese culture.
Yeah, it's really fun to learn by doing something.
听第二段材料，回答第十八至
二十小题。
Good afternoon, everyone.
I'm so happy to give this speech after we move to this new community.
I hope everyone can make more friends and live a happy life here.
Everyone can do something to make a difference to our community.
For example, there are some plastic bags and waste paper hiding under the trees.
This will make our community look dirty and even cause some pollution.
We should get together to collect the rubbish twice a month.
And as you know, some of the elder people are too old to go outside.
Then we can go shopping for them.
Finally, many children stay with their grandparents in our community.
It's difficult for grandparents to help with the children's study.
Why not start a program and help the children with their study?
We can help them with their different subjects and homework.
These things are easy for us to do.
And let's try to make our community a better place.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I'm so happy to give this speech after we move to this new community.
I hope everyone can make more friends and live a happy life here.
Everyone can do something to make a difference to our community.
For example, there are some plastic bags and waste paper hiding under the trees.
This will make our community look dirty and even cause some pollution.
We should get together to collect the rubbish twice a
And as you know, some of the elder people are too old to go outside.
Then we can go shopping for them.
Finally, many children stay with their grandparents in our community.
It's difficult for grandparents to help with the children's study.
Why not start a program and help the children with their study?
We can help them with their different subjects and homework.
These things are easy for us to do.
And let's try to make our community a better place.
you. Thank you.
听力测。
测试到此结束，请把答案转涂到答题卡上